you're saying now that your aunt is so
ты сейчас говоришь что твоя тётка так
bad in California that your aunt
плохо в Калифорнии что тётка там не
can't buy an apartment there and now you
может купить квартиру а теперь ты
're saying that Muscovites can't even
говоришь что москвичи даже в Москве не
buy an apartment in Moscow so Well yes they're looking
могут купить квартиру так Ну да ищут
somewhere in the Moscow region there they're
где-то по подмосковью там детям своим
buying something for their children I understand you understand such is
чтото покупают понял понимаешь такая
life that now they raised our mortgage
жизнь то что сейчас же ипотеку нам
it was 7% now it's
подняли то было 7% сейчас стало
27 Yes this is generally This is generally a market Why
27 Да это вообще Это вообще рынок Почему
did they start removing these non-Russians from
начали вот этих нерусских убирать из
Russia because they understand now
России потому что понимает сейчас
construction will stop they will stop
остановятся стройки перестанут
building When in Great Britain or
строить Когда в Великобритании или во
France or the USA the standard of living falls
Франции или в США падает уровень жизни
it means that before you uh made a
это означает что раньше ты ээ делал
sandwich with red caviar yeah like Wow and
бутерброд с красной икрой да типа Во а
now there's just a slightly thinner layer of
теперь просто чуть-чуть меньше слой
red caviar conditionally yes And in Russia the
красной икры условно да А в России
standard of living is such that Great Britain
уровень жизни такой что Великобритания
won't physically fall there you understand well you
туда не упадёт физически понимаешь ну
know I had a friend who was in London
знаешь у меня знакомая была в Лондоне
I say Well how are the prices there what is there that a goth
говорю Ну как там цены что там что гот
croissant costs 5 pounds there 600 rubles a
круасан стоит 5 фунтов там 600 руб
croissant I can go to the store for 600 rubles to
круасан Я на 600 руб могу сходить в
buy myself something to eat
магазин купить себе что-то поесть
How much does it cost how much  there is a croissant on
Сколько стоит сколько стоит Курасан на
Red
Красной
Square I don't know Well about 150 rubles I think
площади не знаю Ну рублей 150 Я думаю
the more the shorter yes So
побольше будет чем короче да Так вот
look if you come to a
смотри если ты приезжаешь в
tourist city Yes there is a
туристический город Да там есть
tourist infrastructure that
туристическая инфраструктура которая
serves all those who
обслуживает вот этих всех которые
come with money not this cafe on the
приезжают с баблом не это кафе на
outskirts of London where her son lived there
окраине Лондона где сын её жил там
works that is not in the center somewhere
работает то есть это не в центре гдето
there in short she couldn't afford a
там короче она не могла себе позволить
croissant Yes I don't know Well a rich woman
ксан Да я не знаю Ну богатая женщина
apartment in Moscow There mu yes yes she
квартира в Москве Там му да да она не
couldn't afford a crown that is for her it
могла позволить крун то есть для неё это
was essential she remembered the price of a
было существенно она запомнила цену на
croissant Well well she told me a crown
круасан Да ну вот она мне сказала крун 5
costs 5 pounds or even 5 with a croissant that is
фунтов стоит или даже 5 с поно то есть
that and the standard of living that is half she
вот вот и уровень жизни то есть полу
couldn't afford a croissant
не могла позволить ксан
Yes I don't know bought Well probably bought her
Да не знаю покупала Ну навер купила её
son stayed there I don't remember something she
сын остался там я что-то не помня она
stayed there she returned to Russia Well she
там побыла она вернулась в России Ну она
went to her son Her son
к сыну ездила Сын
works And why Son with such expensive
работает А почему Сын с такими дорогими
croissants won't return to Russia with us
кураса нами не вернётся в
doesn't want to And
Россию не хочет А
why Well she likes living in London you know
почему Ну нравится жить в Лондоне знаешь
how this one sings I'll go live in  London
как поёт этот я уеду жить в Лондон
Timati Wait, wait, do I
Тимати Подожди подожди я правильно
understand correctly that she told you how
понимаю что она тебе рассказала как там
bad it is there because a Cro Sanchik costs p
плохо потому что кро санчик стоит там п
or 6 pounds there Yes, and for some reason her son lives
или 6 фунтов Да а её сын почему-то живёт
in this
в этой
unfortunate Britain with such high
несчастной Британии с такими дорогими
prices
ценами
No, no Well, you understand Everyone chooses their own
Да не Ну понимаешь Каждый выбирает себе
life as they want, so I repeat myself to
жизнь как он хочет вот я повторяюсь к
my second cousin who
моей троюродной сестре которая в
lives in California for 20 years, she has lived there, she has
Калифорнии живёт 20 лет прожила она даже
n’t even bought an apartment and she is far from it
квартиры не купила и она далека от этого
And you already told me about that sister
А ты рассказывал уже про ту сестру Да
Yes, yes, and in the same London Sorry,
вот да и в том же самом Лондоне Извини
one question, look, the most important thing is
оди вопрос смотри самое главное можно
how much she bought or didn’t buy, she wants to
сколько купила не купила она хочет
return to
вернуться в
Russia from
Россию из
California I don’t know no, look, if
Калифорнии не знаю нет смотри она если
she can’t buy in California,
она если в Калифорнии не может купить
she will return to Russia in two months
она вернётся в Россию она за два месяца
with her Californian salary, she will
со своим зарплатой калифорнийской сейчас
buy an apartment there now Yes, you
купит там квартиру да у тебя в Старом
have an apartment in Stary Oskol, she
Осколе у неё есть квартира она её даже
doesn’t even sell it and doesn’t try to sell it I understand
не продаёт и не пытается продать понял
why she still has it, she has a nice
почему она всё-таки си у неё Хорошая
three-room apartment, good, why is she
квартира трёхкомнатная хорошо почему она
still sitting in
сидит до сих пор в
California, I don’t know Well, she keeps a backup
Калифорнии не знаю Ну держит запасной
airfield if there  what will happen she
аэродром если там что случится она
will return to Russia for her And so for her
вернётся в Россию для неё А так для неё
Russia is a backup airfield That
Россия запасной аэродром То
is, she still wants to live in
есть она хочет всё-таки жить в
California even though it is
Калифорнии хоть там
worse there No, you know, maybe the picture is more
хуже Нет знаешь ну может там картинка
beautiful there, the coast there, uh, all sorts of
красивее там побережье там ээ всякие
Hollywood stars, you can walk around
звёзды голливудские можно прогуляться по
Hollywood She is for this, I understand, she is
голливуду она ради этого я понял она
for this, I don’t know, I don’t know, you understand,
ради этого не знаю не знаю понимаешь
you understand Now, let’s say in Russia,
понимаешь Вот сейчас допустим в России
here are those who come to Moscow, boys and
вот те кто приезжает в Москву мальчики и
girls Well, the girl Okay, if she is not
девочки Ну девочка Ладно если она не и
pretty, let’s say so, she will find herself a
красивенькая скажем так она найдёт себе
Muscovite, but let’s say it is more difficult for a boy there,
Москвича а допустим пацану сложнее там
even if he finds a good salary there,
даже если он там найдёт хорошую зарплату
a boy can also find a
пацан Москвича тоже может найти сейчас
Muscovite now there are such Muscovites that pano vishy Well, you
москвичи такие есть что пано
know, how to say, there, too, the
вищ Ну знаешь как сказать там тоже
social level must correspond, that is, there and If you consider that
социальный то есть там и Если учесть что
now 400,000 Vad Met costs housing, then
сейчас 400.000 Вад Мет стоит жилья то
This boy will never buy himself
Этот мальчик никогда не купит себе
an apartment in Moscow 400 in Moscow 4 ru kva
квартиры в Москве 400 в Москве 4 ру ква
Met is 4,000 dollars square Met zhi in
Мет это 4.000 долларов квадрат Мет жи в
Moscow
Москве
yes Well, let’s say from the same Old
да Ну допустим из того же самого Старого
Oskol where there me
Оскола где там ме
dollars are worth if he even has
долларов стоит если у него даже есть
some kind of apartment Well he will sell oh Well what is he
квартира какая-то Ну продаст о Ну что он
there he will not buy anything in Moscow
там ничего он в Москве не
And if not then you will not
купит А если этого не то ты не
buy that is it turns out in Moscow
купишь то есть получается в Москве
a Russian cannot buy himself an apartment
россиянин не может купить себе квартиру
and Muscovites cannot buy themselves
и москвичи не могут себе купить
an apartment those who received it from the
квартиру те которые получили от
Soviet you see there is Moscow you are
советского вот понимаешь есть Моск ты
now saying that your aunt is so bad
сейчас говоришь что твоя тётка так плохо
in California that your aunt there cannot
в Калифорнии что тётка там не может
buy an apartment
купить квартиру
and now you are saying that Muscovites
а теперь ты говоришь что москвичи даже в
cannot even buy an apartment in Moscow so Well
Москве не могут купить квартиру так Ну
yes they are looking somewhere in the Moscow region there for
да ищут где-то по подмосковью там детям
their children what
своим что
they buy you see such a life that
покупают понимаешь такая жизнь то что
now our mortgage was raised it was 7%
сейчас же ипотеку нам подняли то было 7%
now it has become
сейчас стало
27 Yes this is generally This is generally a market Why did they
27 Да это вообще Это вообще рынок Почему
start removing these non-Russians from
начали вот этих нерусских убирать из
Russia because they understand now
России потому что понимает сейчас
construction will stop they will stop building
остановятся стройки перестанут
and all this
строить и это всё
you I knew that your mortgage was raised but
ты я знал что у вас ипотеку подняли но
you know it’s just balm for my
ты мне прям знаешь так аж бальзам на
soul there was a mortgage of 7% now 27 It
душу была ипотека 7% теперь 27 Мне
seems to me that those who want to take out a mortgage  something
кажется у желающих взять ипотеку что-то
sharply poushhi yes Well you take there roughly
резко поуши да Ну ты берёшь там грубо
speaking if you used to take a million and
говоря если ты раньше брал миллион и
pay from this million there 15,000 rubles a
платил с этого миллиона там 15.000 руб в
month then now you take a million and
месяц то сейчас ты берёшь миллион и
pay there no longer 15 A7
платишь там уже не 15 А7
[music]
[музыка]
l some May on 30 T then you will pay
л какую-то маю на 30 Т то Ты заплатишь
for these 30 years 40 million rubles That is Well that is
за эти 30 лет 40 млн рублей То есть Ну
like I think here is the whole ro Moscow Here is
бы я думаю вот весь ро Московский Вот
real estate connection stop stop 10 million
это недвижимости связа стоп стоп 10 млн
is 100,000 dollars if you have 4000
это 100.000 долларов если у вас 4000
dollars square This is 25 k this is not even
долларов квадра Это 25 к это даже не
Tiya 25 squares Yes this is very popular
Тия 25 квадратов Да это очень популярное
housing there are there are studios the
жильё есть есть есть студии самая
smallest studio that in Moscow is now
маленькая студия которую в Москве сейчас
being sold by someone I saw the news 8 with by
продают кто-то Я видел новость 8 с по
squares 8 with by there is a toilet well with this with a
квадратов 8 с по там туалет ну с этим с
shower such a shower and this and so the
душем такой души и это и вот такус
room what can you put there
комната что там только можно поставить
Armchair sofa this I just know that these
Кресло диван этот я просто знаю что эти
Khrushchev Yes Khrushchevs were 37 there in short up to
Хрущёв Да хрущевки были 37 там короче до
40 like  Czechs like there yes And less than 30
40 типа чешки типа там да А меньше 30
it was considered something generally simple well I don't
это считалось что-то вообще просто ну не
know how you can live there well there is 14
знаю как там можно жить там ну есть 14
MT there is Well if if 25 squares is
МТ есть Ну если если 25 квадратов это
straight up Fashion is straight up a luxury studio
прямо Мода это прямо студия роскошная
they say that is wait did I
говорят то есть подожди я правильно
understand correctly that in
понял что в
Moscow That is when Russians
Москве То есть когда мне россияне
tell me Muscovites that in California
рассказывают москвичи что в Калифорнии
there is a home in California a house is a
там домой в Калифорнии дом - это дом
two-story house with its own lawn And so
двухэтажный там с своим газончик И так
on and so on and in Russia it turns out a house is well an
дальше а в России оказывается дом это ну
apartment It is 25 squares a studio this is already
квартира Это 25 квадратов студия это уже
considered cool yes
круто считается да
yes Well here in Old Moscow they started building
да Ну вот Старо моско начали строить
studios 18 squares and they cost 2.5
студии 18 квадратов и они стоят 2,5
million imagine And this is without finishing You still
млн прикинь И это без отделки Ты ещё
have to
долже
level the walls plaster them there floors to
выровнять стены оштукатурить их там полы
fill only windows and radiators
залить только окна стоят и радиаторы
willow And this is for a family Of how many
ива А это это на семью Из скольки
people an apartment is well this is for Rodion
человек квартирка ну это для Родиона
Raskolnikov so that he would hate the whole
Раскольникова чтобы он ненавидел весь
world and sharpen his axe some
мир и точил свой топор какую-нибудь
old woman pawnbroker rich from anger
старуху процентщицу богатую от злости
KDV you said yes It was a joke no the
КДВ ты говорил да Это шутка была нет
smallest apartment  in Moscow
самая маленькая квартира в Москве
which was sold in d what year 8 with by
которая продавалась в д чем году 8 с по
squares it was made there converted into an
квадратов её там сделали переделали под
apartment from some hill wait [ __ ]
квартиру из какой-то подсопки подожди
this flag its width is 2 m 25 cm That
сри этот флаг его ширина 2 м 25 см То
is it turns out this apartment in width
есть получается это квартира в ширину
these length these fla width o la it
эти длину этих фла ширину о ла
turns out yes even there someone even
получается да даже там кто-то даже видео
filmed a video and showed it on television to what
снял и показывали по телевидению до чего
Well here Sobyanin Sayani I I walked the width of the
Ну вот Собянин саяни я я прошёл ширину
room it turns out that apartment Well well
комнаты получается той квартиры Вот
gorgeous can you imagine how Everything
ну ну шикарно представляешь как Всё
is done cool But you in
сделано круто Зато ты в
Moscow in Moscow let's say in Moscow
Москве в Москве допустим вот в Москве
it is a great happiness to buy such an apartment
это большое счастье такую квартиру
for 10 million if it is
купить за 10 млн если это
new and 15 can cost 18 if somewhere
новае и 15 может стоить и 18 если где-то
in the center Such an apartment will cost
в центре Вот такая квартира будет стоить
about 20 well not 8.5 but 18 squares somewhere around
около 20 ну не 8,5 а 18 квадратов где-то
18 million 18 million is 180,000
около 18 млн 18 млн - это 180.000
dollars And let's also say there are
долларов Да ещё допустим есть вот
newfangled
новомодные
apartments that do not have a listen
апартаменты которые не имет слуша
wait I just can't understand And according to
подожди я просто не могу понять А по
sanitary standards you can
санитарным нормам у вас можно такое
build something like this There are some
строить Там же есть какие-то
standards there  dream this year
нормы сон в этом году
eh this Moscow Duma and said that
э Московскую эту Думу и сказал что
let's force developers to build these
давайте заставим застройщиков вот эти
studios Let them build but not less than 28
студии Пусть строят но не менее 28
square meters That is, they were forbidden Well, they will
квадратов То есть им запретили Ну они
finish what they are going to build now,
вот то что сейчас построят они достроят
sell it and the next studio will be 28
продадут и следующей студии будет 28
square meters Just look, I saw in short
квадра Просто я смотри я я видел короче
these farms for cows there, it seems, a cow
эти фермы для коров там походу у коровы
cost more, not less, a little less,
больше стоила не меньше чуть-чуть меньше
a little less than a studio for two cows, like
чуть меньше чем студия у двух коров как
one studio This is probably just
одна студия такая Наверное это просто
crazy Well, crazy, well, now look at the
жесть Ну жесть а ну сейчас посмотри
standard for a cow apartment, for example,
норматив для коро квартира вот допустим
in Moscow, here is a full-fledged apartment of 56
вот в Москве вот полноценная квартира 56
square meters, a two-room apartment, well,
квадратов двухкомнатная
close, stop, stop, stop, stop, I have a
вот ну бли сто стоп стоп стоп стоп я вот
standard for the area of ​​​​cows, the standard for the area
норматив площади для коров норма площади
per cow is 30-40 m2
на одну корову составляет 30-40 м
Well, in Ukraine, you don't have this pppp
к Ну а у вас в Украине такого нет пппп
there is, if the standard for the area per cow is 30-40 m2,
есть если норма площади на коро 30-40 м
then if one Russian lives in mi
то если один россиянин жит в ми
squares, then five Russians Russians
квадратах то пять россиянин россиян
correspond to one cow according to housing
соответствует одной коровы по жилищным
standards
нормам
Cool Well, you know, many  they leave
Прикольно Ну понимаешь многие уезжают за
10 km from Moscow where the prices are more or less
10 км от Москвы там где на более менее
normal But this Change to the
нормальные цены Но это Измени на
electric train there it takes half an hour to get to
электричка там полчаса ехать до
Moscow that is
Москвы то есть
well those
ну те
studios in
студии в
Moscow
Москве
to buy here I am those I am not
купить вот я те Я тея не
lying some kind of this level Now you have the
вру какой-нибудь этот левел Сейчас тебе
most here the most sanitary standards
вот самое вот само санитарные нормы
for keeping cattle here
содержания крупного рогатого скота вот
look here in Ukraine
смот вот в Украине У
We have now Thanks to this mortgage prices
нас сейчас Благодаря этой ипотеке цены
fell note dog became cheap money
попадали ноте дога стала дешёвые деньги
ran out
закончились
Well approximately for 30 heads there an area of
Ну примерно для 30 голов там площадь в
300 MT in the middle 10 per
300 МТ в средине 10 на
head less than a cow Yes Yes Well it turns out that
голову меньше коровы Дада Ну получается
even according to these calculations for 30
что на это даже по этим расчётам на 30
cows Yes on average per cow it turns out
коров Да в среднем на корову получается
10 square meters more than per Russian
10 квадратов больше чем на россиянина
Yes you have Gilles very much
да у вас Жиль очень
surprised that in Belgorod an apartment
дее удивился что в Белгороде квартира
costs almost three times more than in
стоит чуть ли не в три раза дороже чем в
Kharkov Sorry Kharkov is the second city of
Харькове Извини Харьков город второй
Ukraine And why is
Украины А почему
it because
так потому что
greed That is you are now Moscow in
жадность То есть ты сейчас Москве в
Moscow - this is greed the greed of
Москве - это жадность жадность
developers
девелоперов
and they will not add up prices for themselves now
а они себе цены не сложат вот сейчас
you  I'll show you something
тебе покажу что-нибудь
interesting but it's true it's a big
интересное но это правда это большая
studio
студия
that is well if a grandmother died in
то есть ну если там умерла бабушка в
Kharkov and bequeathed an apartment to Belgorod residents
Харькове и завещала квартиру белгородцы
then he won't buy anything in Belgorod after selling the apartment there
то он Белгороде продав там квартиру
Well, excuse me What happiness
ничего не купит Ну извини Какое счастье
if a grandmother died in Belgorod there and a
если бабушка в Белгороде умерла там а
grandson in Kharkov then he will buy himself
внучек в Харькове то он себе купит у
an apartment from me my relatives sold a three-room apartment Well then it's been
родственники продали трёшку Ну тогда ещё
eleven years they are from the Lugansk
одиннадцатый год они из Луганской
region but their grandmother lived in Staro
области а вот бабушка у них в Старо
Mosko a three-room apartment
моско жила трёшка
cost an average price of about 1N 700 then
стоила средняя цена где-то 1н 700 тогда
it's 30 rubles a dollar cost they sold it for
это 30 руб стоил доллар они продали за
1N 200 we were kind of surprised that it was so
1н 200 мы как бы удивились что так
cheap they
дёшево они
kissed I generally I can't understand one thing if
поце Я вообще я не могу понять одно если
you have such a beard with those apartments And
у вас такая борода с теми квартирами И
so on why are you spending a lot of money
так дальше зачем вы куча денег тратите
on the war against
на войну против
Ukraine well so that NATO doesn't kill us you
Украины ну чтоб нас НАТО не убило
know So maybe Let NATO
понимаешь Так может Пусть бы вас НАТО
capture you and finally live in normal apartments
захватило и в нормальных квартирах бы
Well that's it that's it a studio apartment
Ну вот вот вот квартира студия
ad Come on
объявление Давай
And in Moscow Well that's the center of Moscow
А в Москве Ну это центр Москвы
177.8 square meters  costs
177,8 квадрата стоит
17,100,000 rubles 1 square meter Meter 10,000
17.100 000 руб 1 квадра Мет 10.000
bucks
баксов
17. 100,000 170,000 bucks Well, 1
17. 100.000 170.000 баксов Ну 1
square meter is 10,000 bucks, it turns out
квадратны метр 10.000 баксов получается
yes a
да
million
миллион
rubles and I don’t know here there is a layout
руб и вот я не знаю тут планировка есть
but the apartment is good in the center of
но Квартира хорошая центр
Moscow Well, I don’t know, you see the ad
Москвы Ну вот объявление не знаю видишь
Well, you can see something like this a
Ну что-то видно такое
small country room You see Yes,
дачный номер небольшой Вот видишь Да
I see this room there is an apartment there is
вижу вот эта комната есть квартира там и
a bedroom and a kitchen, those are small kitchens arranged
спальня и и кухня те кухня устроенная
this is how cool Muscovites live
маленькая вот так живут крутые москвичи
17 million you understand Even if you have a
17 млн ты понимаешь Вот даже если у тебя
good salary in Moscow How much
хорошая зарплата в Москве Ты сколько
money do you need to earn for this
тебе надо денег чтобы заработать на эту
studio So this is not housing this is
студию Так это не жильё это это
this yes I agree yes The question is how to
это да я согласен да Вопрос как там
reproduce there The question is, you say
размножаться Вопрос вот ты говоришь
Why why do they reproduce in Dagestan in
Почему почему в Дагестане размножаются в
Moscow Moscow is in first place in terms of
Москве Москва вот на первом месте по на
per woman indicator St. Petersburg one whole
одну женщину показатель Питер одна целая
per woman 1.1
на одну женщину 1,1
children next comes rich Moscow
ребнка следующее идёт богатая Москва на
per woman
одну женщину
1.2 children that is and even these indicators
1,2 ребёнка то есть и то эти показатели
give  Chechens Tajiks who give birth there
дают чеченцы таджики которые там рожают
Even in Dagestan this indicator
Даже даже в Дагестане этот показатель
fell below two somewhere 3 years ago
упал меньше двух вот где-то 3 года назад
that is they are also already
то есть они тоже уже там
rolling there now that
катятся сечас те
is
сть
Dagestan
Дагестан
so here is
так вот
Sepa two Yes indeed in Dagestan
Сепа двух Да действительно в Дагестане
less than two I looked There is
меньше двух Я смотрел Там есть зубаревич
such a woman Zubarevich an economist for the regions and
такая женщина экономист по регионам и
she said that Dagestan is already
она рассказала это то что уже и Дагестан
dying out
вымирает
IT but excuse me how they live they
ИТ но извини меня они как живут они дома
build houses of 200 to 300 square meters Yeah that is
строят 200 по 300 квадратов Угу то есть
there well I don’t know what they have there they also have
там ну не знаю что там у них у них тоже
something But in short well I just can’t understand
чтото А короче ну я вот не могу понять
so
всё-таки так
uh just from the money that was
ээ просто из тех денег которые были
thrown into the war in Ukraine Yes I don’t know it would
брошены на войну в Украину Да я не знаю
be possible to build stupidly
можно было бы построить тупо
in short a house for every person in Russia they
короче дом каждому человеку в России
would not have built don’t keep in mind that this money could
бы не имей в виду что эти деньги можно
be like people in Russia who live
бы вот как люди в России которые живут
without apartments huddle there for half their lives collect
без квартир ютятся там полжизни собирают
for 8 MT square meters Yes why do they
на 8 МТ квадратны Да почему они
support this war against
поддерживают вот эту войну против
Ukraine And you know throwing so much money to the
Украины Да и выброс стольких денег на
wind
ветер
Ukraine is also to
знаешь Украина тоже в этом
blame for this sat
виновата сидели
And not  climbed into this and would have given the Russian
И не лезли в эту на и Дали бы русскому
language some kind of status, a piece of paper, written
языку какой-то статус бумажку написали
that the Russian language has official status, you
что имеет официальный статус русский
can write a statement to the
язык можно там написать там заявление в
police there, something like that, because half of
полицию там что-то такое потому что у
your country is in Russian and no one would
вас полстраны на русском и вас бы никто
touch you, that is,
трогал То есть
you are homeless Muscovites, Belgorod residents, Petersburgers,
вы бездомные москвичи белгородцы питерцы
and so on, yes, instead of
И так дальше да вместо того чтобы
worrying about how you will get your children a
переживать как себе получите своим детям
normal apartment and live and enjoy
нормальную квартиру и жить радоваться
life, you are worried that in Ukraine
жизни Вы переживаете что в Украине
someone was not allowed to write a statement
кому-то не разрешили написать заявление
to the police in Russian, am I right in
в полицию на русском языке я правильно
understanding? No, there are also risks. What are these, too?
понимаю нет тоже риски Какие что это
Look again. Well, okay, let's say that the same
смотри Ну вот Окей допустим вот тот же
Putin. He
Путин Он
has a certain percentage of
имеет там определённый процент от продаж
gas sales to Europe, of oil sales to Europe, the
газа в Европу от продаж нефти в Европу
entire Russian elite is raw materials, that
вся Российская элита она сырьевая то
is, any city that has
есть там любой город который имеет
some kind of raw materials income is
какую-то сырьевой там доход это
considered a rich city, if
считается богатый город если
there is some kind of pumping plant,
какой-нибудь там насосный завод
this is And so he, realizing that in this regard he
это И вот он понимая что он в этом плане
depends on Europe, that almost all the money
зависит от Европы что почти все деньги
that comes to Russia is
которые приходят в Россию они вот
European, understands that Europe
европейские и понимает что Европа
is trying to make Ukraine into
пытается сделать Украину в качестве вот
some kind of
какого-то
springboard for an offensive on  Russia
плацдарма для наступления на Россию
is starting this
начинает эту
special operation absolute In economic
спецоперацию абсолютную В экономическом
terms murder for
плане убийстве для
Russia here
России вот
No, well, it was clear from the very beginning
Да не ну это с самого начала было
Because all this golden
Понятно Потому что вся эта золотая
youth who could buy themselves
молодёжь которая могла себе купить и за
an apartment in Moscow for 300 million and
300 млн квартиру в Москве и за миллиард
build a house in the Moscow region and in Nizhny Novgorod for a billion
построить дом в Подмосковье и в нице
they lived and all over Europe their yachts were taken away from them
жили они и по всем Европам у них забрали
you know They turned out to
яхты они понимаешь Они настолько
be so either for them or for them I understand
оказались то ли им то ли им я понимаю
there is a palace in Nizhny Novgorod here we have
там в дворец стоит вниц вот у нас
Usmanov oligarch Starooskolsky has a
Усманов олигарх старооскольский имеет
metallurgical plant yoke which he is
металургический завод иго который он
Uzbek by the way he is Uzbek And he has the
узбек кстати он узбек А и у него яхта
biggest yacht bigger than the king of
самая большая больше чем у короля
Saudi Arabia he left in Hamburg
Саудовской Аравии он в Гамбурге оставил
if if he already on February 18 it was
если если он уже уже 18 февраля было
clear that something bad would happen I would, for
понятно что будет что-то нехорошее Я бы
example, call this captain and
вот допустим позвонил этому капитану и
say take it to neutral waters and then
сказал вывози в нейтральные воды а потом
we will think what to do next with this yacht
будем думать что дальше с этой яхтой
maybe somewhere in Murmansk
делать там может куда-нибудь в Мурманск
damn we will send it Let it winter
блин её отправим Пусть там она зимует
there he left it and now it was
там он оставил её и теперь её
confiscated he is now suing that it was I who
Конфисковали он тепер судится что это я
did not want anything there  Yes, I understand that
там ничего не хотел Да я понимаю что там
he has a palace in London there, he still has one
он там дворец в Лондоне у него остался
more time, look, I
там подожди ещё раз ещё раз смотри я
still can't understand, Europe and
всё-таки не могу понять вот Европа да
Russia supply them with gas and so on. Yes,
Россия поставляет им газ и так дальше Да
why would Europe make some kind of a foothold
с Зачем Европе делать какой-то плацдарм
and attack
и нападать на
Russia, well, if he has intelligence,
Россию ну если если у него есть разведка
it reports such information that he is there
она докладывает такую информацию что он
first, well, I'm like Crimea is there now
сначала там ну я типа сейчас Крым там
because in Crimea they want to join Russia,
потому что в Крыму хотят в Россию там от
so yes,
этого да
[music]
[музыка]
I'll join in with the truth, and I kind of
присоединюсь к правде и я как бы Украину
slow Ukraine down, it won't be able to join NATO
заторможена не сможет войти в НАТО
because it will have undefined
потому что у неё будет неопределённые
borders, but he didn't attack
границы но он не стал нападать полностью
Ukraine completely, it was not to his advantage, he
на Украину ему это невыгодно было он
understood that in 2014, that in
понимал что в четырнадцатом году что в
general, the
общем-то
economy would improve, but in
экономики наступит но в двадцать втором
2022, he understood that these
году он понимал что вот эти риски
terrible economic risks, they completely
страшные экономические Они полностью
outweigh the risks of a
перевешивают рисками уже там вторжения
military invasion of Russia, and he decides that Yes,
военного в Россию и он решается что Да
he understands again, who should have
он понима е ещё раз Кто кто должен был
invaded Russia, who are the Germans,
вторгаться в России кто немцы друзья
Putin's friends, the French, the British, who should have
Путина французы англичане кто должен был
sent their troops to ROSI. Apparently you. Apparently
послать свои войска в РОСИ Видимо вы
you, well, why, why should he.  they give such
вы ну почему почему ему дают такую
information that he just, well, you saw this
информацию что он просто ну ты видел это
address when he recognized the DPR LPR and he
обращение когда он признал ДНР лнр и он
sits in the office and says that
сидит в кабинете и говорит что вот у
his
него
voice and face are shaking and everything is like that, that
трясётся голос и лицо всё вот так вот то
is, he himself is in shock from what he is
есть он сам в шоке от того что он
saying but he is simply pinned to the wall by
говорит но его просто припёр к стенке
some terrible data that he
уже какими-то страшными данными Что ему
needs to do something and he understands that the
надо что-то делать и он понимает что
Ukrainian army, like they said
украинская армия вот как рассказывали
that in Donetsk when they fought that you with
что в Донецке когда воевали что вы с
some kind of machine guns from the Afghan war,
какими-то автоматами с Афганской войны
some kind of completely unprepared
какими-то вообще не подготовленная
insignificant army that could have been
ничтожная армия которую можно было
defeated in 2 weeks and enter Kyiv and
разбить за 2 недели и войти в Киев и во
Lvov and then armed it
Львов а потом её вооружились
[music]
[музыка]
there and everything will be fine ki Eve There are
там и всё будет хорошо ки Еву Осталось
a few days left But these are
несколько дней Но это
people I myself remember this right away
люди я сам помню вот это вот сразу
political shows started on
политические шоу начались по Первому
Channel One this damn grandson of Molotov is standing there
каналу этот блин внук Молотова там стоит
these experts are saying that Kyiv the fall of
эти эксперты говорят что Киев падение
Kyiv this is all there are just a few hours
Киева это вот всё там вот считанные часы
left this is well
осталось это ну
you and I Yes we have not seen each other for about
вы мы с тобой Да мы с тобой так не
six months now I
виделись гдето уже може полгода Мне
like the change in your consciousness
нравится изменение твоего сознания
Why Yes you are like that you are such things
Почему Да ты такие ты ты такие вещи сто
wait a minute you  such a feeling Yes, what are you
подожди ты такое ощущение Да что ты
now like I don’t know how this riverman of the
сейчас как не знаю как этот речник
Armed Forces of Ukraine or whatever he’s
Вооружённых сил Украины или что как
broadcasting you understand I’m looking at it I’m thinking is it
вещает понимаешь я так смотрю думаю это
you or not you stop standing I’m not talking about that
ты или не ты стой стоит я не в том дело
I’m talking about what it means they showed up
я говорю в том что значит его припёрлись
urgently to enter the territory of Russia, the
срочно заходить на территорию России на
territory of Ukraine and save the residents of
территорию Украины и спасать жителей
Donetsk and Lugansk who have been killing and bombing for 8 years
Донецка и Луганска которые 8 лет Убивали
and that is, like, that’s all, that’s all,
бомбили и то есть вот как бы вот всё всё
that’s all, that’s all that’s needed, that’s what he negotiated with Natasha for six months
вот вот вот надо вот это он полгода с
that they wouldn’t
Натой там договаривался что они Та не
accept Ukraine into NATO they didn’t give
примут Украину в НАТО они ничего не дали
him anything he got offended by them Shaigumrov started
он на них обиделся начал шайгумаров
Come on, come on, look, it’s
Давай давай так смотри
already been almost 3 years since the beginning of its
ээ уже прошло почти 3 года от начала сво
Ukraine is bombing Ryazan with drones in short, an
Украина дронами бомбит Рязань короче
oil refinery, it’s fresh I don’t
нефтеперерабатывающий завод он свежий не
know there Kazan Izhevsk that is, they’re
знаю там Казань Ижевск то есть на такие
already taking the Russian economy out to such distances, they’re
расстояния уже экономику России выносят
just
просто просто да северные потоки
blowing up the Northern Streams now they’ll
взорвали сейчас ещё по турецкому
stop transmitting this gas according to Turkish law Well, what’s
прекратят передачу этого газа Ну что Ну
going on, the murder of
идёт убийство
Europe is going on LNG is more expensive than this gas from the
Европы СПГ дороже чем вот этот газ из
pipeline Europe somehow lives Europe lives and
трубы Европа как-то живёт Европа живёт а
phew  yells visit fi he needs 5 billion for
фи фи орёт визит фи ему надо 5 млрд для
slo tsat I'll tell you I'll tell you because
сло цат я тебе скажу я тебе скажу потому
fi Yes, this is small, this is
что фи Да это маленький это человек
Putin's man, just yes This is a dude who
Путина просто да Это чувак который там
either has some dirt on him or he was
либо компромат на него какой-то либо его
bought a long time ago and brought to power Yes,
купили давно так и привели к власти Да
this is just Putin's chick Yes, now Fitz
это просто Путинская чка Да сейчас фиц
Von Slovakia saw They went out to Maidan
Вон Словакии видел Вышли да на Майдан
against Fitz, which is big,
против фиц какой большой
also paid for by
тоже проплачено
America slu he said He said on the
Америкой слу он сказал Он сказал в
scale of Europe Europe 120
масштабах Европы Европа 120
ml Do I understand correctly I understand correctly
мл я правильно понимаю я правильно
that everything that is being done against Putin's
что всё что делается против путинских
is all paid for by America
это всё проплачено Америкой
Yes, it seems to me that on the contrary it protects
Да так мне кажется о наоборот защищает
the interests of Slovakia, here is the orba IFI of
интерес именно Словакии вот орба ИФИ
normal politicians who remained in Europe,
нормальных политика остались в Европе
who may still have Vucic, but he is not
которые ещё может ещё вучич но он он не
in
в
Europe, but
Европейском а
fi Why won't Fitz come out so that
фи Почему фиц не выйдет тогда чтобы
Slovakia doesn't leave
Словакия не вышла из
the European Union And why will he
Евросоюза А зачем он
come out, you understand, all of Eastern Europe is
выйдет он понимаешь вся Восточная Европа
gobbling up the same Germany and France
объедает Ту же самую Германию и Францию
England saw this in time and waved
Англия это увидела вовремя и помахала
goodbye to the European Union like oh
ручкой европейскому Союзу типа о До
Goodbye, we didn't feed anyone, we,  for
свидание мы никого не кормили мы мы за
We have always lived at the expense of half the world And
Мы за пол за счёт полмира всегда жили А
here we have to feed these Slovaks and Hungarians there
тут мы должны там этих словаков венгров
Poland Poland, supported by
кормить Польша Польша на обеспечению у
Germany,
Германии
thanked Germany by building a
отблагодарила Германию тем что построила
military base against Russia on the border with Germany, which Duda
Германией военную базу которая Дуда
said I will call it the Ford Trump Foundation
сказал Я назову его фонд Форд Трамп
Then Biden came and said no, it will not
Потом пришёл байден сказали нет это не
be Fort Trump, it will be called by
будет фортом трампом это будет
another name now
по-другому названию сейчас снова
TM has returned again now it is also translated that
вернулся ТМ сечас тоже его переве то
is, the Poles are generally such a
есть поляки - это вообще народ такой
slippery people, that is why they have suffered so much all their
скользкий поэтому они так мучились всю
lives that they are constantly
жизнь что их постоянно
[music]
[музыка]
beating how hard it is to live in
дубасить как тяжело жить сейчас в
Bulgaria now all the young people have left
Болгарии вся молодёжь уехала из
Bulgaria because
Болгарии пото
agriculture is going bankrupt people see
сельское хозяйство разоряется люди видят
that somewhere in Germany it is good to pay
что там где-то в Германии хорошо платт
They are leaving there there are no young people, pensioners are the
Они уезжают туда молодежи нет пенсионеры
only ones who
одни
work I am right I understand correctly
работают я прави я правильно понимаю
that in all countries everything is bad, it is ruined
что во всех странах плохо все разоряется
only in Russia it is
только в России
good well damn well and in Russia Whoever
хорошо ну блин ну и в России Кто как
got settled in understands it is good in Germany there are
Устроился понима вез любо в Германии
poor people there are rich then why are you
бедные есть богатые то зачем ты мне
telling me Bulgaria as an example if you
пример Болгарии говоришь если ты
say everywhere there are poor and
говоришь везде есть бедные и
rich Well in Bulgaria they say that it is very
богатые Ну в Болгарии говорят что очень
difficult  life That's right they're right
тяжёлая жизнь Вот вот прямо они прямо
let's do it where is life harder in Bulgaria
давай так где тяжелее жизнь в Болгарии
or in
или в
Russia I don't know I've never lived in Bulgaria
России не знаю я в Болгарии не жил
can you look for me uh eight by eight
можешь мне поискать ээ восьми на восемь
square meters of Sofia these new buildings
квадратов Софии эти новостроечный
[music]
[музыка]
can you for me in Sofia we Let's compare
можешь мне вот в Софии мы Давай сравним
Sofia
Софи
to No well let's say in the Moscow region here's a
к Не ну допустим в Подмосковье вот
studio here's a studio 26 square meters a
студия вот студия 26 квадратов
royal studio costs 6 million rubles that's a
королевская студия стоит 6 млн руб это
royal studio Yes it's even a
по королевская студия Да она даже
separate room 10 square meters royal Well
отделена комната 10 ква королевская Ну
26 square meters is big and royal I understand
26 квадратов большая а королевская понял
Well not 15 but 26 is
Ну не 15 а 26 это
already r
уже р
plus Okay let's do it today something is already very
плюс Хорошо давай сегодня что-то сильно
long we'll finish everything I'll run
долго уже будем заканчивать всё побегу
further it's interesting we started Yes we started about
дальше интересно мы начали Да начали о
religion By the way I have a question about religion And
религии Кстати у меня вопрос о религии А
you were a Rodnover And what are you doing I was I'm
ты же был родноверы А что ты это я был я
now from Yes my views have changed
сейчас от Да у меня изменились мои
and you are there with a Greek Catholic
воззрения и вы там с греко-католик
something there like I was Yes I was at first
что-то там ка я был Да я был сначала
Look I was an unbeliever at first but then I
Смотри я был сначала неверующий да потом
seemed to be interested in Khri
вроде как бы интересовался Хри
then in short I was a Rodnover then I became this
потом короче был родном потом стал этим
atheist So  transformed you
атеистом Так трансформировались у тебя
had such an expression
тако было выраже
so let's move on Oh that's how it
ла так едем дальше Ох вот так оно
turned out an interesting conversation in short what shall
интересный разговор получился короче что
we say Russians Russians have already begun
мы скажем россияне россияне начали уже
to see the light They have begun to see something
прозревать Начали что-то прозревать
deadly for the Russian economy it
убийственно для экономики российской
was impossible Kyiv in 3 days and do you remember
нельзя было Киев за 3 дня а вы помните
how they sang six months ago a year ago
как они пели ещ полгода назад год назад
Yes And now something And how the mortgage for them
Да А сейчас что-то А как ипотека им
became not 7% ​​but 27 so something understood
стала не 7% а 27 так что-то поняли
therefore everyone who said sanctions do not
поэтому все кто говорили санкции не
affect everything affects brick by brick it's just that
влияет всё влияет по кирпичику просто
these processes do not happen immediately sanctions
эти процессы происходят не сразу санкции
act Yes but the chains which are
действуют Да но цепочки которые
production
производственные
which are suppliers and so yes All these
которые поставщики и так да Все эти
business processes they are still by inertia
бизнес-процессы они ещё по инерции
somewhere they are dragging somewhere they are trying to sing there it is
где-то тянутся где-то пробуют пропет там
pressing there it is pressing and that's it And
дожимает там дожимает и всё И вот
look and the puzzle is coming together weak loop
смотрите и пазл складывается сла петля
uh Pulls Pulls strangles strangles and that's it 20 and
ээ Тянет Тянет душит душит и всё 20 и
now you understand yes here a Russian is sitting
теперь понимаешь да тут россиянин сидит
and scratching his
и чухается
head because in Moscow he has eight
репу потому что у него в Москве да восем
squares eight squares of this  fir tree I don't
квадратов восем квадрато этой ёлке Я не
know I looked at the flag as an example and the
знаю я же на примере флага смотрела да
studio and so so that the magnifying glass is a rock like a
студия и так так что лупа цю скалу лайк
squeak comment and drop this video to yours
писка комент и скиньте Цей видос вашим
Glory to
мым Слава
Ukraine write to Telegram right now
Украине пись на й Telegram прям зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through scarg ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show to
багато видео не показую
people at times I don't show information about
людям вчасно не показуе информация про
streams That's why we Mali
стрими Тому для того щоб ми Мали
operational links are written right now
оперативний звязок пишиться прямо зараз
and while there in Telegram OKM videos there are also
а пок там в телегра окм видео ще теж
useful information and we owe
цикава корисна информация и ми повинни з
you constant operational
вами тримати постийний оперативный
links
звязок
independently in that che will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine write
YouTube Слава украини пиши
with
с